In planning this lesson, we knew we wanted to focus on highway driving,
このレッスンをプランニングする中で 高速道路での運転に着目した時
but we still debated what states we should use for our finite state machine.
finite state machine がどの状態を使用すべきか考えていました
We quickly agreed on three,
3 つのことはすぐに同意しました といのも
since it seemed to us like these were
これらは最低限のことのようで
the bare minimum and that a single lane change wouldn't suffice.
また車線を 1 つ変更することは難しくないからです
And we also agreed to rule out a lot of states because most of
また 多くの状態を規則から除外することに同意しました
these can be thought of as various implementations of the keep lane state.
その理由は そのままの車線の状態にするさまざまな実装として考えられるからです
But these last two, prepare lane change
でも最後の 2 つは 左に車線変更する準備をし
left and prepare lane change right, we were unsure about.
右に車線変更する準備をすることだと思うけど よくわかっていませんでした
Eventually, we did decide to use these states for these lessons.
最終的に これらの状態をこれらのレッスンに使うことにしました
So we should probably clarify what we mean by these states.
これらの状態で意味したことが明確になるはずです
Let's start by imagining what vehicle behavior would
これらの 2 つの準備状態なしで 自動車がどのように動作するかを
look like without these two prep states.
イメージ化するところから始めましょう
First, let me explain how this example will work.
まず この例がどのように機能するか説明します
Up here we have a two-lane highway with traffic driving to the right.
ここでは 2 車線の高速道路で右車線を走っています
This is our self-driving car and other traffic is shown in red.
これが自動運転車です 別の道路は赤で示されます
As you watch this animation,
このアニメーションを見ているように
you should imagine watching from a helicopter which is flying
自動運転車の目標速度で
above the highway at the self-driving car's target speed.
高速道路の上を飛んでいるヘリコプターから見ていることを想像します
These red trails indicate the relative speed of other vehicles.
これらの赤い跡は 他の自動車の関連速度を示しています
In this situation, the vehicles in lane one are moving faster
この状況では 車線 1 の自動車は
than we are while the vehicles in lane two are moving slower.
車線 2 の自動車よりも速く走っています
When we only have three states plus a fourth ready state,
3つの状態と 4 番目の準備状態だけがあるとき
the finite state machine looks like this.
finite state machine はこんな感じになります
We'll assume that as we begin watching we are already in the keep lane state.
我々が監視し始めるときには、既に我々は車線維持状態にあると仮定します
Now before we watch what happens to our vehicle when it uses this finite state machine,
この finite state machine を使用すると私たちの自動車に何が起こるか見ていく前に
let me explain what these states mean.
これらの状態の意味を説明します
The lane keep state attempts to stay in
車線をそのままにする状態では その車線の真ん中を走ることで
the current lane by staying near the center line for that lane.
現在の車線のままにしようとします
So thinking in finite coordinates,
そのため 有限座標で考えたとき
we might just say that target d for the vehicle is whatever the d for the lane is.
車線の d がなんであろうと自動車のターゲット d だといえます
And for the s direction,
s 方向では
keep lane state attempts to drive at the vehicle's target speed when that's feasible,
車線をそのままにする状態は 適していれば自動車の目標速度で運転しようとしますが
but when it's not, it will try to drive at whatever speed is safest for the lane.
そうでないときは その車線で安全な速度で運転しようとします
For lane changes the goal is to move from the initial lane to the target lane.
車線変更の場合 ゴールは最初の車線から目標の車線に移動することです
The d behavior is what you might expect to move left or right as appropriate.
d の動きは 適切に左または右に移動しようとすることです
So the target d is the d for whatever lane is to
よって 目標 d は 自車の現在の車線の左または右であっても
the left or right of the ego's current lane.
その d です
For s, the same rules as lane keeping apply.
s の場合 車線をそのままにするのと同じ規則が適用されます
The vehicle will try to drive at the target speed,
自動車は目標速度で運転しようとしますが
but if that's not feasible,
適切でない場合は
then it will drive at whatever speed is safe for the initial lane.
その車線で安全な速度で運転しようとします
Now, let's observe the vehicle's behavior as we move forward in time.
では そうこうするうちに前に進んでいるので自動車の動きを見ていきましょう
For the first few timesteps,
最初のいくつかの時間ステップでは
we see that the ego-vehicle gets closer and closer to vehicle
左車線の自動車が自車を抜かすときに
2.2 while the vehicle in the left lane pas the ego-vehicle.
自車が自動車 2.2 にどんどん近づいてくるのがわかりました
And during this time the vehicle remains in the lane keep state
また この時間 安全な車線変更をするには十分な車間距離がなかったので
since there isn't really enough gap to make a safe lane change.
自動車は車線をそのままにする状態でした
Note that at this point the ego-vehicle does
よく見ると この時点で状態を変更しても自車は
begin to slow down even though it doesn't change state.
減速し始めます
That's because the lane keep state contains this behavior.
それは 車線をそのままにする状態にこの動きを含むからです
When the target speed is no longer feasible,
目標速度が適切ではなくなると
it will adjust speed to something safe for the lane.
その車線で安全になるよう速度を調節します
At this point, the vehicle has decided that the lane change left is the best move.
この時点では 自動車は左への車線変更が一番いい選択だと決定しました
Now, in the lane change state,
では 車線変更の状態で
you can see the vehicle has moved left in its lane but hasn't adjusted its speed.
自動車がその車線の左側に寄っているけれど 速度を調節してないことがわかります
This is consistent with the rules we defined for lane change behavior.
これは車線変更動作に定義した規則に従っています
At this point, the vehicle has crossed the dotted line,
この時点では 自動車は点線の車線を越えるので
so its current lane is the left lane.
現在の車線が左車線です
Now it wants to transition back to the lane keep state to stay in this lane,
この車線で車線をそのままにする状態に戻って
and when it does that,
それを行うと
it immediately starts accelerating so it can get to a speed that's safe for this lane.
すぐに加速が開始されこの車線で安全な速度にできます
Right now it is moving at the same speed as other traffic in the left lane,
今は 左車線と同じ速度で動いています
which it can continue doing until it passes the vehicles on the right.
右の自動車がそれを追い越すまでそのままにできます
Even though this worked, there were some problems.
これがうまくいくとしても 何か問題があります
First, even when it was clear that there was
まず 左側に十分な車間距離があったことが明確な時でも
a gap we could probably move into on the left,
自動車にその車間距離に
we had no way to tell the vehicle to try to get alongside that gap.
並行して走るようには言えません
We had to just wait for the gap to get close to us.
その車間距離が近くになるまで待たなければなりません
Second, this lane change wasn't all that safe.
2 番目に この車線変更はそれほど安全ではありませんでした
Ideally, we would have been able to get closer to
実際に 車線を変更する前に
the left lane speed before actually making the lane change.
左車線の速度に近づくことができたはずです
Third, it isn't clear when we would have turned on the turn signal in this scenario.
3 番目に このシナリオでは 曲がる指示器を出したときがあまり明確ではなかったです
The turn signal is the responsibility of the behavior team and
曲がる指示器は 動作チームの責任で
ideally we would like to turn it on
実際に車線変更を開始する前に
a few seconds before we actually start changing lanes.
数秒間出したままにしておきます
Using this finite state machine,
この finite state machine を使用すると
it would have been hard to do that.
それをするのが難しくなります
To address that problem,
その問題を示すには
we can introduce a prepare for lane change state.
車線変更状態の準備を説明する必要があります
In this state we do whatever we can to prepare for a lane change left or right,
この状態では 車線変更左または右を行うために できることは何でもします
which means in the d directions we still can
これは d 方向では この現在の車線にいるままにできますが
stay in this current lane but in the s direction we
s 方向では
tried to match the position and speed of some gap in one of the adjacent lanes.
車間距離の位置とその速度に合わせようとすることを意味します
This is also when we would turn on the appropriate signal.
これは適切な指示器を出すときでもあります
We also changed the finite state machine to look like this.
また finite state machine をこんな感じに変更しました
And note that the only way to change lanes is to first prepare for a lane change.
車線変更をするには まず車線変更の準備をします
Let's see what that would look like.
その準備がどのようなものか見てみましょう
At the first timestep we can decide to prepare
最初の時間ステップでは この車間距離をみて
for a lane change by tracking this gap over here,
車線変更を準備することを決定できます
which allows us to immediately start slowing down.
これで すぐに減速し始めることができます
At this point, the car may begin slowly increasing
この時点では 左車線の速度に近づけるため
speed to get closer to the left lane speed,
車がゆっくり加速する場合もあります
and at this point the vehicle has reached the same speed as the left lane traffic
また 左車線の交通速度に達して
and is in a good position to execute a lane change, which it begins here.
車線変更を実行するのにいい位置にいる場合 ここで始めます
From here on, everything looks pretty similar to before.
ここからは 前と同じような感じです
With these added states,
これらの追加された状態により
we're now able to perform a lane change more safely and efficiently.
より安全で効率的に車線変更を行うことができるようになりました